## **David Quintero**

#### **SUMMARY**

Software engineer with 3 years of training as a Full-Stack and Front-End web developer. With a passion for building responsive, elegant and engaging experiences with future friendly web technologies such as React, Node.js, Express and MongoDB. I invite you to please take a moment to **explore my developer portfolio** and experience my skills for yourself at: <a href="https://davidquintero.dev">https://davidquintero.dev</a>

#### FEATURED PROJECTS & EXPERIENCE

# Web Scraper/Twitter Bot for @lesswrong\_bot (Node.js, MongoDB) September 2021

- This Node is bot scrapes the latest posts from LessWrong.com (an online community dedicated to human rationality and AI development) and tweets the latest entries every hour. Technologies used were MongoDB and Node is as well as the Twitter API.
- This bot allows anyone who wishes to keep up with the latest publications from this community to receive **hourly** updates if they turn on notifications for its Twitter handle at <a href="https://twitter.com/lesswrong">https://twitter.com/lesswrong</a> bot source available in my GitHub.

## HomeWorks (Full-Stack Lead Generation App | React, Node.js, Express, MongoDB) – 200+ hours project January 2021

- Commissioned by a home remodeling and services company, HomeWorks allows a customer to request services at their home address. The app organizes the request by dates and keeps track of the flow from initial contact, estimate and service completion. It features a testimonial system, use of the Google Maps API, real-time updates with WebSockets, user registration, authentication & authorization, i18n language internationalization and a mobile-first responsive layout.
- This full-stack project combines every aspect of web development. It is also a fully deployed commercial application generating revenue for its company. This **featured project** can be accessed through <a href="https://homeworks.davidquintero.dev">https://homeworks.davidquintero.dev</a> A four-step tour is available. Source available in my GitHub.

#### **BOOTCAMP CERTIFICATIONS**

#### Full Stack Developer Certification | 1200 hours coursework

freeCodeCamp.org • 2019-2020

**JavaScript Data Structures & Algorithms** • Provided a comprehensive understanding of the JavaScript language, Object-Oriented Programming (OOP), as well as developing a problem-solving mental model. **Responsive Web Design** • Understanding semantic HTML5 and CSS3 as well as important UX/UI methodology. **Frontend Libraries** • Creating applications using React, managing states, abstraction and components. **APIs and Microservices** • In depth exploration of Node.js and the Express library to create and web servers, API end points and microservices.

#### **FULL-STACK TECHNOLOGIES**

Front End: React | HTML5 | CSS3 | TailwindCSS | AdobeXD | Figma Back End: Node | Express | MongoDB | GraphQL | Postman DevOps: Linux | Docker | GitHub Actions | git | yarn | npm Testing: Jest | Selenium

#### **WORK HISTORY**

#### Freelance Web Developer

UpWork

March 2020 - Present, Remote

- Have developed and customized Shopify store themes using Liquid, JavaScript, HTML5 and CSS3.
- Linux server administration and DNS projects.
- WordPress blog set-up and development for academic professionals.

#### Store Manager

The UPS Store

February 2016 - March 2020, Orlando, FL

- I was a store manager and lead graphic designer. Had the privilege of supporting a small team provide exceptional service to the community promoting a culture of inclusivity and kindness.
- I worked on hundreds of marketing projects for all types of businesses and causes in the downtown Orlando area. We offered in-store industrial printing capability, booklets, postcards, posters, banners, foam-core mounting, etc. Highly creative and highly rewarding jobs. This position exposed me to hundreds of business ventures, marketing strategies, success stories, and good creative energy and collaboration with clients when designing their artwork and delivering finished products.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### A.A. General Studies (Enrolled)

Valencia College • Orlando, FL • 2022 • 3.0 GPA



The UPS Store®
3208 C East Colonial Drive
Colonial Landings Shopping Center
Orlando, FL 32803
407.897.3542 Tel
407.898.8209 Fax

To whom it may concern:

I am writing with the utmost confidence to recommend David Quintero for the position he is seeking at your company. I have known David since 2016 when I purchased my The UPS Store. David was an employee of the previous owner when I bought the store. He was the only employee that chose to stay on with a new unfamiliar owner. Right from the onset he became an invaluable member of my team. David continued to grow and was an outstanding manager. Without David as my manager for the first 3 years in business I do not think our store would have grown at the rate it did. David Quintero would be a great asset to any employer looking for an excellent, self-motivated worker.

Steve Wrobel- Owner, The UPS Store 0407

This certifies that

## David Quintero-Lopez

has successfully completed the freeCodeCamp.org

## JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

Developer Certification, representing approximately 300 hours of coursework

Quincy Larson

Executive Director, freeCodeCamp.org

Verify this certification at: https://www.freecodecamp.org/certification/netk/javascript-algorithms-and-data-structures

# freeCodeCamp(A)

Issued October 17, 2020

This certifies that

## David Quintero-Lopez

has successfully completed the freeCodeCamp.org

## **APIs and Microservices**

Developer Certification, representing approximately 300 hours of coursework

Quincy Larson

Executive Director, freeCodeCamp.org

Verify this certification at https://freecodecamp.org/certification/netk/apis-and-microservices

This certifies that

## David Quintero-Lopez

has successfully completed the freeCodeCamp.org

### Front End Libraries

Developer Certification, representing approximately 300 hours of coursework

Quincy Larson

Executive Director, freeCodeCamp.org

Verify this certification at https://freecodecamp.org/certification/netk/front-end-libraries

freeCodeCamp(A)

Issued May 11, 2020

This certifies that

## David Quintero-Lopez

has successfully completed the freeCodeCamp.org

## Responsive Web Design

Developer Certification, representing approximately 300 hours of coursework

**Quincy Larson** 

Executive Director, freeCodeCamp.org

 $\label{thm:continuous} Verify this certification at: https://www.freecodecamp.org/certification/netk/responsive-web-design and the statement of the statement$